Our students have all the knowledge they need to build a search engine,
我们的学生有建立一个搜索引擎需要的知识
but what are they missing?
但他们缺少什么呢？
Well, a few thousand of these.
嗯 数千个这样的东西
We're standing in front of the Google server rack.
我们就站在谷歌服务器机架前面
This is a web server, but it's using Ethernet to connect these different boards,
这是一个网络服务器 但它是使用以太网连接这些不同的主板
which are actually separate computers that they've put together in a rack.
这些主板实际上是单独的计算机 这些计算机都一起放在机架上
These are just generic PCs, because you can run a search engine at home on one computer,
这些只是普通的个人电脑 因为你可以在家里的一台计算机上运行搜索引擎
but it's not going to have a very big index.
但它不会有很大的索引
How many are we talking about--10s?
我们在谈论多大的——几十？
Many, many, many thousand.
很多很多很多万
Google was not a particularly well-known one it its early years.
谷歌在早期不是特别著名
Most of these search engines--today we think of them as being incredibly wealthy companies.
其中大部分搜索引擎——今天 我们认为它们是非常富裕的公司
At the time they were mostly losing money.
当时 他们大多亏本
They had venture capitalists put money in but they
他们吸引了风险资本家的投资 但是
basically didn't make enough money from selling ads to pay their bills.
通过卖广告 基本上没赚足够的钱支付账单
Search engines actually go back before the web.
事实上 搜索引擎可以追溯到网络之前
On the Internet there were several search engines.
因特网上有几个搜索引擎
The closest to what we have today might be WAIS, done in the late '80s,
最接近我们今天使用的引擎可能是 WAIS 完成于八十年代末期
and that let you search different servers over the Internet.
可以让你在互联网上搜索不同的服务器
Then we have, for instance, the CERN Virtual Library,
然后我们有了 例如 欧洲粒子物理实验室虚拟图书馆
which was done by Tim Berners-Lee, the man who invented the Web,
这是有发明网络的蒂姆·伯纳斯李成立的
but that wasn't really like a modern search engine.
但那不真的像现代的搜索引擎
It was more like a library cart catalog where you have categories.
更像你有的不同类别的图书馆卡片目录
Early Yahoo was like that as well.
早期的雅虎也是这样的
The one that got the most recognition was Alta Vista,
最受大家认可的是 Alta Vista
and this was kind of like the Google of its day in the late '90s.
这是有点像90年代末的谷歌
One that was a little bit different was Ask Jeeves,
这个有点不同于 Ask Jeeves
which was a search engine, but it was also meant to be a natural language query.
这是一个搜索引擎 但它意味着是一个自然语言查询
You could say, "What's the capital of Spain," and it would give you the answer.
你可以问 "西班牙的首都在哪里" 它会给你答案
Google borrowed an idea from a little search engine called GoTo.com,
谷歌借用了一个小搜索引擎 GoTo.com 的想法
which was to not just have ads but to sell the search terms themselves.
即不只是有广告 还卖自己的搜索条件
So like when you go to Google now, and you see the "sponsored results,"
当你现在去谷歌 你会看到"赞助的结果"
those are actual terms related to what you're searching for, but they're also ads.
这些是你正在搜索的实际条件 但它们也是广告
That just took off. People really responded to that.
这也成功了 人们真的回应了
That actually brought the entire search industry
这实际上使整个搜索行业
from on its way down to being one of the most profitable parts of web commerce.
成为了网络商务最盈利的部分之一